Md Fuad Hasan

③ fusan.live | **in** fusan | **ℳ** FuSan21

Location: Dhaka Cant., Dhaka, Bangladesh Email: fuad.antor@gmail.com | Mobile: +8801521392165

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

I am a computer science professional over 4 years of experience in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP and Python. I have knowledge of popular frameworks such as Laravel, MERN, FastAPI and experience with REST APIs. I have worked with architectural patterns like MVC, MVP, Microservices and Serverless. Additionally, I have experience with Kotlin as an android app developer, which has further enhanced my versatility in software development.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

: JavaScript, PHP, HTML, CSS/SCSS, Python, Java, Kotlin Languages **Frameworks** : Laravel, React.js, Express.js, Node.js, FastAPI, TailwindCSS

Libraries : Material, Flowbite, Selenium, SQL Alchemy, JWT, Bcrypt, PHPUnit, Junit, Espresso

: MySQL, MongoDB, CF D1, CF KV, FireStore **Databases**

DevOps : Github Actions, Docker

: AWS EC2, Apache, Nginx, Caddy, CF Workers, CF Pages, CF Access, Vercel, Linux, cPanel **Technologies**

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Web Developer

May 2023 - Present Remote - Dhaka, Bangladesh

Tekinouchi

- Maintained strong skill set in various technologies to update, optimize and rectify issues with corporate website
- Maintained version control systems such as Git in order to keep track of changes made to the source code
- Provided technical support and troubleshooting services when needed
- Designed creative user interfaces for websites with a focus on usability
- Developed, tested and debugged web applications using HTML5, CSS3, JS and Laravel
- · Modified existing WordPress plugin or theme to add functionality
- Configured databases such as MySQL in order to store data securely
- Integrated third-party APIs into web applications for enhanced functionality

Frontend Web Developer

Apr 2023 - Jul 2023

Fiver

- Specialized in crafting custom WordPress dashboards to match client requirements using ACF, UiPress
- Worked on designing tailored widgets in a custom dashboard using HTML, CSS, JS and Wordpress Hooks
- Skilled in optimizing dashboard usability and efficiency
- Troubleshot and fixed bugs and issues in the backend

Self-Employed Feb 2019 - Jul 2023

Wordpress Content Creator/Developer

- Delivered high-quality, insightful, informative, and entertaining written content
- · Set up the hosting environment in AWS EC2, Lightsail and custom cpanel hostings
- Implemented automated scraping using Selenium python library and published content using wordpress REST API

EDUCATION

Brac University CGPA: 3.82 Jan 2020 - Jun 2024

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

PUBLICATIONS

Dynamic Authentication Protocols for Advanced Security in Federated Metaverse Systems (In progress) NSysS 2024

Clinique Accounts Management Web App

Node.js, Express.js, HTML, CSS

Live

- Different CRUD based operations exposed using a RESTful API made with Node.js
- Exposed POST, GET, PATCH and DELETE HTTP methods using Express
- Developed efficient patient management system for adding and adjusting patient information
- · Automated calculation of different fees, income, expenditure for each department
- Designed a user-friendly interface for outside patients to select pathology tests
- Ensured compliance with web security best practices, including CSRF protection and role-based access control
- · Created admin dashboard for comprehensive income and expenditure overview

Vehicle Accessories Inventory Shop

Laravel, TailwindCSS, MySQL, Flowbite, Faker

Source Code

- Developed using Laravel and Tailwind CSS, ensuring a robust backend with a modern, responsive frontend.
- Includes real-time inventory tracking, advanced search functionalities, and user-friendly interfaces.
- Implemented secure user authentication and authorization systems, including role-based access control.
- Created an intuitive shopping cart and checkout process, ensuring a smooth user experience.
- Managed product catalog and inventory using Laravel's Eloquent ORM and database migrations.
- Implemented advanced search and filtering functionalities for products.
- Developed an admin panel with CRUD operations for managing products, orders, and customer data.
- · Compliance with web security best practices, including CSRF protection and input validation using middleware.
- Used Faker library to add dummy data.

PocketKaraoke

Kotlin, Firebase, MVP, Instrumented Tests

Source Code

- Developed an android app using Kotlin and MVP architecture.
- Implemented Firebase Authentication and utilized FireStore for online database
- Implemented sing-along feature with real-time lyrics
- · Integrated performance-based scoring system
- Created real-time frequency graph
- Added audio effects (reverb, echo, pitch change)
- · Enabled sing-off challenges with friends
- Conducted **Instrumented Tests** for robust app performance

Furnicraftbd Bootstrap, Serverless Live

- Designed and developed a clean and modern portfolio using HTML, CSS, JS on Bootstrap framework
- Optimized website for speed and user experience
- Utilized responsive design to ensure compatibility across all devices
- Deployed on GitHub pages via GitHub Actions

Federated Metaverse Dynamic Authentication

Fast API, SQL Alchemy, JWT, PKA

Source Code

- Developed a dynamic authentication model for the Federated Metaverse to authenticate users across servers
- Implemented servers using Python FAST API following Model-Controller-Service along with Pydantic Schema
- Designed and managed separate MySQL databases for server authentications and userdata
- Utilized RS256 key pairs for JWT tokens for secure user authentication
- Executed cryptographic challenge-response mechanisms with **PKA** for user login and verification
- Implemented secure mode and device integrity checks for authentication requests
- Enabled token-based access to metaworlds with mechanisms for JWT token renewal and management
- Ensured robust and versatile authentication while supporting various algorithms based on requirements

LANGUAGES

Bangla English Professional